Guide to the D.T. Suzuki Documentary Project Collection, 2002-2005 RL.10036
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
D.T. Suzuki Documentary Project collection
2002-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Goldberg, Michael
RL.10036
4.5 Linear Feet 3 boxes, 35 digibeta tapes, DVD user copies
D.T. Suzuki was a scholar of Zen Buddhism, often attributed with introducing Zen to the West. He was born in Japan in 1870, and after working as a translater in the United States, began writing books and essays about Zen. He spent much of his life traveling around the United States speaking about Eastern religions and teaching at Columbia University. An enormously influential figure, he is cited by artists and thinkers as disparate as Carl Jung and John Cage as an important influence on thier work. The D.T. Suzuki Documentary Project Collection is comprised of taped material, amassed by Michael Goldberg in the making of his documentary A Zen Life - D.T. Suzuki. It consists of a series of interviews conducted between the years 2002 and 2005, as well as a lecture given at Tokyo University by Prof. Brian Victoria.
Collection Overview
The D.T. Suzuki Documentary Project Collection consists of 35 Digital Betacam (Digibeta) cassette tapes, along with DVD use copies, of interviews and one lecture concerning the life and work of D.T. Suzuki.
The tapes are arranged alphabetically by name of the individual granting the interview or delivering the lecture. The interviews were conducted between the years 2002 and 2005 by Michael Goldberg in the making of his film, A Zen Life - D.T. Suzuki. The subjects of the interviews include Suzuki's professional colleagues, family members of friends of Suzuki, Zen religious leaders and thinkers, and those who have been influenced by Suzuki's work. They were conducted primarily in the United States and Japan. The lecture, entitled D.T. Suzuki and Japanese Militarism, was given by Brian Victoria, a professor of Buddhist studies at Tokyo University in 2004.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Use copies are available in the collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
Daisetz Teitaro (D.T) Suzuki was a Japanese author often credited with introducing Zen Buddhism to the west. Born in 1870, he was not himself a monk, but he had a deep understanding of Eastern and Western religions. He began as a translator, working with Dr. Paul Carus to translate the Tao Te Ching from ancient Chinese, but it was not long before he began writing his voluminous body of work. In his life he published over a hundred books and had a profound impact on a wide range of thinkers and artists, such as Carl Jung, John Cage, and Gary Snyder. His most famous work, An Introduction to Zen Buddhism, was published in 1934. He died in 1966, after having spent years giving lectures around the United States and Europe and teaching at Columbia University from 1952 to 1957.
Zen Buddhists -- Japan.; Zen Buddhists; Audiovisual materials; Digital Betacam (TM); Documentary Film; Buddhist scholars -- Japan.; Goldberg, Michael; Suzuki, Daisetz Teitaro
- Interviews, 2002-2005; 1; 4.5 Linear Feet
  - Aitken Roshi, Robert, 2003 June 12; 1
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 12; 01:29:19 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Aitken Roshi, Robert: interview at his home, Honolulu, Hawaii, 2003, June 12 (1 of 2)
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 12; 01:24:42 (Box 1)
      Aiken Roshi, Robert: interview at his home, Honolulu, Hawaii, 2003, June 12 (2 of 2)
  - Bando, Shojun, 2003 March 7; 2
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 March 7; 01:10:58 (Box 1)
      Bando, Shojun: interview at Hoonju Temple, Ueno, Tokyo, 2003, Mar. 7
  - Carus, Alwin, Blouke Carus, and Edward Carus Jr., undated; 3
    - Original digibeta master tape, undated; 00:28:08 (Box 1)
      Carus, Alwin, Blouke Carus, and Edward Carus Jr.: interviews in LaSalle and Peru Ill. and Honolulu, Hawaii, undated
  - Dalenberg, Claude Ananda, 2004 September 16; 4
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 September 16; 00:21:31 (Box 1)
      Dalenberg, Claude Ananda: interview in his home, San Francisco, Calif., 2004, Sept. 16
  - de Bary, William Theodore, 2003 June 20; 5
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 20; 00:39:01 (Box 1)
      de Bary, William Theodore: interview at Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 2003, June 20
  - Edel, Marjorie, 2003 June 11; 6
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 11; 00:40:11 (Box 1)
      Edel, Marjorie: interview at her retirement home, Honolulu, Hawaii, 2003, June 11
  - Foster Roshi, Nelson, 2003 June 17; 7
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 17; 00:41:28 (Box 1)
      Foster Roshi, Nelson: interview at Ring of Bone Zendo, Nevada City, Calif., 2003, June 17
  - Franck, Frederick, 2003 June 21; 8
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 21; 01:10:13 (Box 1)
      Franck, Frederick: interview at Pacem in Terris, Warwick, N.Y., 2003, June 21
  - Hayashida, Kumino, 2002 August 31; 9
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2002 August 31; 01:35:35 (Box 1)
      Hayashida, Kumino: interview at her daughter's home, Yokohama, Japan, 2002, Aug. 31 (1 of 2)
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2002 August 31; 01:23:32 (Box 1)
      Hayashida, Kumino: interview at her daughter's home, Yokohama, Japan, 2002, Aug. 31 (2 of 2)
  - Hino, Kenshi, 2005 February 11; 10
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2005 February 11; 00:16:48 (Box 2)
      Hino, Kenshi: interview at Saishoji Temple, Ishikawa Prefecture, Japan, 2005, Feb. 11
  - Hinohara, Shigeaki, M.D., 2003 January 20; 11
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 January 20; 00:37:55 (Box 2)
      Hinohara, Shigeaki, M.D.: interview at St. Lukes Internation Hospital, Tokyo, Japan, 2003, Jan. 20
  - Inoue, Zenjo, 2002 May 24; 12
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2002 May 24; 00:49:07 (Box 2)
      Inoue, Zenjo: interview at Tokeiji Temple, Kita-Kamakura, Japan. 2002, May 24
  - Ishiura, Newton, 2003 June 14; 13
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 14; 00:56:03 (Box 2)
      Ishiura, Newton: interview in Sacramento, Calif. 2003, June 14
  - Johnston, William, S.J., 2004 March 26; 14
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 March 26; 00:20:22 (Box 2)
      Johnston, William, S.J.: interview at Sophia University, Tokyo, Japan, 2004, Mar. 26
  - Kadowaki, Kakichi, 2004 March 26; 15
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 March 26; 00:27:40 (Box 2)
      Kadowaki, Kakichi: interview at Sophia University, Tokyo, Japan, 2004, Mar. 26
  - Kano, Hakuo, 2002 August 11-13; 16
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2002 August 11-13; 01:45:04 (Box 2)
      Kano, Hakuo: interviews at his home near Mt. Hiei, Shiga, Japan, 2002, Aug. 11, 2003 Apr. 13
  - Kyger, Joanne, 2004 September 16; 17
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 September 16; 00:19:29 (Box 2)
      Kyger, Joanne: interview at her home, Bolinas, Calif., 2004, Sept. 16
  - Mitchell, Elsie, 2003 June 23; 18
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 23; 01:37:37 (Box 2)
      Mitchell, Elsie: interview at her home, Cambridge, Mass., 2003, June 23
  - Nishimura, Eshin, 2003 April 7; 19
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 April 7; 00:43:37 (Box 2)
      Nishimura, Eshin: interview at Hanazono University, Kyoto, Japan, 2003, Apr. 7
  - Oda, Hiroko, 2003 March 4; 20
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 March 4; 00:54:44 (Box 2)
      Oda, Hiroko: interview at her apartment, Tokyo, Japan, 2003, Mar. 4
  - Okamura, Mihoko, 2005 February 13; 21
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2005 February 13; 00:56:23 (Box 2)
      Okamura, Mihoko: interview at Heian Kaikan, Kyoto, Japan, 2005, Feb. 13
  - Richie, Donald, 2004 March 18; 22
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 March 18; 00:21:46 (Box 3)
      Richie, Donald: interview at Enkakuji Temple, Kita-Kamakura, Japan, 2004, Mar. 18
  - Sakamoto, Hiromu, 2003 April 13; 23
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 April 13; 00:43:19 (Box 3)
      Sakamoto, Hiromu: interview at his home, Kyoto, Japan, 2003, Apr. 13
  - Sato, Taira Kemmyo, 2004 September 26, 2005 December 10; 24
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 September 26, 2005 December 10; 01:43:28 (Box 3)
      Sato, Taira Kemmyo: interviews at Three Wheels Temple, London, UK, and Shogyoji Temple, Kyushu, Japan, 2004, Sept. 26 and 2005, Dec. 10
  - Smith, Huston, 2003 June 15; 25
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 15; 00:58:26 (Box 3)
      Smith, Huston: interview at his home, Berkeley, Calif., 2003, June 15 (1 of 2)
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 15; 00:34:44 (Box 3)
      Smith, Huston: interview at his home, Berkeley, Calif., 2003, June 15 (2 of 2)
  - Synder, Gary, 2003 June 17; 26
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 17; 01:22:22 (Box 3)
      Synder, Gary: interview at his home, Nevada City, Calif., 2003, June 17
  - Stunkard, Albert, M.D., 2003 June 19; 27
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 19; 01:54:38 (Box 3)
      Stunkard, Albert, M.D.: interview at The University of Pennsyvannia School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pa., 2003, June 19 (1 of 2)
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 June 19; 00:24:27 (Box 3)
      Stunkard, Albert, M.D.: interview at The University of Pennsyvannia School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pa., 2003, June 19 (2 of 2)
  - Tamaru, Noriyoshi, 2003 October 25; 28
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2003 October 25; 00:54:41 (Box 3)
      Tamaru, Noriyoshi: interview at Taisho University, Tokyo, Japan, 2003, Oct. 25
  - Victoria, Brian, 2004 June 14; 29
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 June 14; 01:29:31 (Box 3)
      Victoria, Brian: lecture, "D.T. Suzuki and Japanese Militarism," at Tokyo University, Tokyo, Japan, 2004, June 14 (1 of 2)
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 June 14; 01:37:44 (Box 3)
      Victoria, Brian: lecture, "D.T. Suzuki and Japanese Militarism," at Tokyo University, Tokyo, Japan, 2004, June 14 (2 of 2)
  - Victoria, Brian, 2004 May 29; 30
    - Original digibeta master tape, 2004 May 29; 00:21:11 (Box 3)
      Victoria, Brian: interview at Uchiyama Gudo's grave, Rinsenji Temple, Hakone, Japan, 2004, May 29